[man speaks Sardaukar]
[slow dramatic music playing]
[rhythmic thumping music
playing]
[girl in English]  My planet
Arrakis is so beautiful
when the sun is low.
Rolling over the sands...
you can see spice in the air.
[inhuman growl]
At nightfall,
the spice harvesters land.
The outsiders
race against time
to avoid the heat of the day.
[thumping music tempo
increasing]
They ravage our lands
in front of our eyes.
Their cruelty to my people
is all I've known.
[dramatic music playing]
These outsiders,
the Harkonnens,
came long before I was born.
By controlling
spice production,
they became obscenely rich.
Richer than
the Emperor himself.
[exhales sharply]
-[stabs]
-[man screaming]
[gunshot]
[explosions]
[screaming]
Our warriors couldn't free
Arrakis from the Harkonnens,
but one day,
by Imperial decree,
they were gone.
Why did the Emperor
choose this path?
And who will
our next oppressors be?
[inhales deeply]
[breathes deeply]
[soft music playing]
[Lady Jessica]
It's good you're up early.
Your father wants you
in full dress
before the Emperor's Herald
arrives.
Full dress?
Military?
-Ceremonial.
-[Paul sighs]
Why do we have to go
through all this
when it's already
been decided?
Ceremony.
Mm.
Thank you.
If you want it,
make me give it to you.
Use the Voice.
Mom, I just woke up.
Give me the water.
The glass can't hear you.
Command me.
[wind chimes tinkling]
[distorted voice]
Give me the water.
[wind chimes stops tinkling]
Almost.
[normal voice] Almost?
Bene Gesserit skills
take years to learn, Paul.
-[Paul] Mm-hmm.
-You look tired.
More dreams?
No.
[narrator over speakers]
Extreme temperatures
and treacherous weather events
make life outside the cities
of Arrakis truly hostile,
with sandstorms
powerful enough
to cut through metal.
Only the native tribes
known as the Fremen
have adapted
well enough to survive.
Preferring to inhabit the
remotest regions of Arrakis,
the Fremen share
the deep desert
with the giant sandworms
known to the Fremen
as  Shai-Hulud.
Long exposure to spice
has given the tribe
their characteristic
blue eyes,
the Eyes of Ibad.
Little else is known
of the Fremen,
except that they are
dangerous and unreliable.
Fremen attacks
make spice harvesting
extremely hazardous.
For the Fremen, spice
is the sacred hallucinogen
which preserves life
and brings
enormous health benefits.
For the Imperium,
spice is used
by the navigators
of the Spacing Guild
to find safe paths
between the stars.
Without spice,
interstellar travel
is impossible,
making it by far
the most valuable substance
in the universe.
[slow dramatic music playing]
[slow dramatic music
continues]
Smile, Gurney.
I am smiling.
How much will it cost them,
traveling all this way
for this formality?
Three Guild Navigators.
A total of 1.46 million,
62 solaris, round trip.
By the grace of
Shaddam IV of House Corrino,
ascendant to
the Golden Lion Throne
of Padishah Emperor
of the Known Universe,
I stand before you
as Herald of the Change.
We are witnessed by members
of the Imperial Court,
representatives
of the Spacing Guild
and a sister
of the Bene Gesserit.
The Emperor has spoken.
"House Atreides
shall immediately
take control of Arrakis
and serve as its steward."
Do you accept?
[Leto] We are House Atreides.
There is no call
we do not answer,
there is no faith
that we betray.
The Emperor asks us
to bring peace to Arrakis.
House Atreides accepts.
[officers chanting]
Atreides! Atreides! Atreides!
Your seal.
So, it's done?
It's done.
[Lanville] How was it?
[Duncan over mask]
Stabilizers are too loose.
-We'll dial it in.
-Thank you, my friend.
[Lanville] Got it.
[Paul] Duncan.
[Duncan]  My boy.
-[Duncan chuckles]
-Hey. Hey.
[Duncan]  Paul, my boy.
So, you're going
to Arrakis tomorrow.
With the advance team.
Yes, I'm going
to Arrakis tomorrow
with the advance team.
I'd like you
to take me with you.
You would?
Well, that's too bad.
'Cause no.
[Paul] Duncan.
Are you trying
to get me court-martialed?
What's going on?
Can I trust you
with something?
Always. You know that.
[sighs]
I've been having dreams.
About Arrakis and the Fremen.
[ethereal music playing]
[Duncan] Okay.
So?
I saw you.
With the Fremen.
Ah.
So, I do find them.
There you go. That's a good
omen right there, right?
Lanville!
I saw you lying dead.
Fallen in battle.
It felt like
if I had been there,
you'd be alive.
First off, I'm not gonna die.
You're not
taking me seriously.
That's why
you want to come with me.
Listen.
Dreams make good stories,
but everything important
happens when we're awake.
'Cause that's when
we make things happen.
Look at you.
Put on some muscle?
I did?
No.
Hey.
See you on Arrakis, my boy.
[sighs]
[animal chirping]
Father, I'd like to ask
to join Duncan Idaho
on his scout mission
to Arrakis tomorrow.
I've studied the Fremen
language, I'd be an asset.
Out of the question.
You'll travel
in a few weeks to Arrakis,
like the rest of us.
I've been training
my whole life.
What is the point
if I'm not allowed
to face some actual risk?
You know why, Paul.
You're the future
of House Atreides.
And Grandfather
fought bulls for sport!
Yes.
And look where that got him.
I need you by my side.
When we get to Arrakis,
we'll face enormous danger.
What danger?
The Fremen? The desert?
Political danger.
The Great Houses
look to us for leadership,
and this threatens
the Emperor.
By taking Arrakis from the
Harkonnens and making it ours,
he sets the stage for a war
which would weaken
both houses.
But if we hold firm,
and tap the true power
of Arrakis,
we could be stronger
than ever.
What does that mean?
Mining spice,
keeping the Fremen
in their place?
We'd be no better
than Harkonnens.
No.
By making an alliance
with the Fremen.
That's what I've sent
Duncan Idaho to arrange.
Here on Caladan,
we've ruled by air power
and sea power.
On Arrakis, we need
to cultivate desert power.
I want you sitting in
on my Council.
Learn what I do.
What if I'm not, Dad?
Not what?
The future of House Atreides.
[Leto sighs]
I told my father
I didn't want this either.
I wanted to be a pilot.
You never told me that.
Your grandfather said,
"A great man
doesn't seek to lead.
He's called to it,
and he answers."
And if your answer is no...
you'll still be the only thing
I ever needed you to be...
my son.
I found my own way to it.
Maybe you'll find yours.
In their memory...
give it a try.
[grunting]
[Gurney] Don't stand
with your back to the door.
How many times
do we have to tell you?
[Paul grunts]
I could tell it was you
by your footsteps,
Gurney Halleck.
[Gurney] Someone
might imitate my stride.
[Paul] I know the difference.
Are you the new
Weapons Master?
With Duncan Idaho gone,
I must make do as best I can.
Choose your blade.
I've had quite a day, Gurney.
Give us a song instead.
[smacks lips] That's rude.
[Paul grunts]
[powers up]
[device beeps]
[Paul groans]
[panting]
[Gurney] Come on.
Come on.
Old man.
[exhales forcefully]
[Paul grunts]
[device beeps]
Ah, the slow blade
penetrates the shield.
[groans]
I guess I'm not
in the mood today.
-Mood?
-Yeah.
What's mood to do with it?
You fight
when the necessity arises,
no matter the mood.
Now fight!
[both grunting]
Come on!
-[device beeps]
-I have you.
Aye.
But look down, my lord.
You'd have joined me in death.
I see you found the mood.
[Gurney panting]
[devices deactivate]
Will it be that bad?
You don't get it, do you?
You don't really understand
the grave nature
of what's happening to us.
For 80 years,
Arrakis belonged
to House Harkonnen.
80 years of owning
the spice fields.
Can you imagine the wealth?
Your eyes.
I need to see it in your eyes.
You never met
Harkonnens before, I have.
They're not human,
they're brutal!
You have to be ready.
[dramatic ominous music
playing]
[Rabban] Lord Baron.
[Vladimir] Rabban.
The last of our ships
have left Arrakis.
It's done.
[Vladimir] Very good.
Uncle, how can we
let this happen?
How can the Emperor
[shouting]
take everything we've built
and give it to that Duke?
How?
Don't be too sure
it's an act of love.
[breathes heavily]
What does he mean?
When is a gift not a gift?
The Atreides' voice is rising,
and the Emperor
is a jealous man.
A dangerous, jealous man.
[ominous music playing]
[voices chanting indistinctly]
[voices continue chanting]
[voices fade]
Paul.
[softly] Paul, wake up.
What's wrong?
Get dressed and come with me.
What is this?
The Reverend Mother
Gaius Helen Mohiam is here.
She was my teacher
at the Bene Gesserit school.
She's now Truthsayer
to the Emperor himself.
She would like to meet you.
Why?
She wants to know
about your dreams.
How does she know
about my dreams?
And why is Dr. Yueh here?
He only needs a moment.
[Dr. Yueh] Hello, young master.
Your mother asked me
to check your vitals.
What's happening?
[whispering in Mandarin]
[in English] His heart
is strong as ever, my lady.
[in sign language]
Paul...
[eerie voices]  Who are you?
Defiance in the eyes.
Like his father.
Leave us.
[whispers]
You must do everything
the Reverend Mother tells you.
You dismiss my mother
in her own house.
[Mohiam in distorted voice]
Come here.
Kneel.
How dare you use
the Voice on me?
[in normal voice] Put
your right hand in the box.
Your mother bade you obey me.
[Paul breathes heavily]
I hold at your neck
the Gom Jabbar.
A poison needle.
Instant death.
The test is simple.
Remove your hand from the box
and you die.
What's in the box?
Pain.
-[scoffs]
-No need to call the guards.
Your mother stands
behind that door.
No one would get past her.
[Paul]
Why are you doing this?
An animal caught in a trap
will gnaw off
its own leg to escape.
What will you do?
[high-pitched whirring]
[groans]
[exhales sharply]
[sobbing softly]
[shudders]
-[grunts in pain]
-Silence.
[Paul breathing raggedly]
-[Paul grunts in pain]
-[shuddering]
I must not fear.
[stifles grunt, whimpers]
[suppressed groan]
Fear is the mind-killer.
Fear
is the little death
that brings obliteration.
-[whirring intensifies]
-[Paul grunts]
And I'll face my fear
and I'll permit it
to pass over me
and through me.
[ominous music playing]
[dramatic lamentation music
playing]
[searing]
And when it has gone past...
I will turn the inner eye
and see its path. [gasps]
[sobs] And where the fear
has gone,
there will be nothing.
Only I will remain.
Enough.
-[panting]
-[whirring fading]
Like sifting sand
through a screen,
we sift people.
If you had been unable
to control your impulses,
like an animal,
we could not let you live.
You inherit too much power.
What, because
I'm a duke's son?
Because you are Jessica's son.
You have more
than one birthright, boy.
Jessica?
You've been training him
in the Way.
Tell me about these dreams.
-I had one tonight.
-What did you see?
A girl.
On Arrakis.
Have you dreamt of her before?
Many times.
Do you often dream
things that happen
just as you dreamed them?
Not exactly.
Goodbye, young human.
I hope you live.
[Lady Jessica]
Did you have to go that far?
[Mohiam] You chose
to train him in the Way,
in defiance of our rule.
He wields our power.
He had to be
tested to the limits.
So much potential,
wasted in a male.
You were told
to bear only daughters.
But you, in your pride,
thought you could
produce the  Kwisatz Haderach.
Was I wrong?
You're lucky he didn't die
in that room.
If he is The One,
he has a long way to go.
His Sight is barely awakened,
and now he goes into the fire.
But our plans
are measured in centuries.
We have other prospects
if he fails his promise.
Do you see so little hope?
[Mohiam] On Arrakis,
we have done
all we can for you.
A path has been laid.
Let's hope
he doesn't squander it.
[voices murmuring
indistinctly]
[breathes heavily]
[Lady Jessica] Paul.
[Paul] What does it mean?
That I could be The One?
[Lady Jessica] You heard.
The Bene Gesserit serve
as powerful partners
to the Great Houses,
but there's more to it.
You steer the politics
of the Imperium
from the shadows.
I know.
You don't know everything.
For thousands of years,
we've been carefully
crossings bloodlines
-to bring forth...
-The One?
A mind...
powerful enough
to bridge space and time.
Past and future.
Who can help us
into a better future.
We think he's very close now.
Some believe he's here.
All part of a plan.
[slow dramatic music playing]
[slow dramatic music
continues]
[spaceship lands]
Shield.
[metallic groan]
[metallic thudding]
[door opens]
"My lungs taste
the air of Time,
Blown past falling sand..."
[bagpipe playing]
[band playing
patriotic music]
Thufir Hawat.
Young master!
How does it feel
to walk on a new world?
Exciting, to say the least.
My lord.
How are you, old friend?
My advance team
has secured the city.
We're still smoothing out
a few rough spots.
My lady.
[woman]  Lisan al-Gaib!
[crowd clamoring]
[man]  Lisan al-Gaib!
Lisan al-Gaib!
[woman 2]  Lisan al-Gaib!
[crowd chanting]
Lisan al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
Don't be fooled
by the welcome.
They follow
their old masters' rules.
Mandatory attendance.
That's Harkonnen love
out there.
[crowd continues chanting]
Atreides!
[soldiers chanting]
Atreides! Atreides! Atreides!
Atreides! Atreides!
[Thufir] Let's get you
out of the sun.
The heat can kill
in this place.
[ornithopters powering up]
They were pointing at us.
What are they shouting?
Lisan al-Gaib.
"Voice from the Outer World."
It's their name for "messiah."
It means the Bene Gesserit
have been at work here.
Planting superstitions.
Preparing the way, Paul.
These people
have waited for centuries
for the  Lisan al-Gaib.
They see you,
they see the signs.
They see
what they've been told to see.
We're good to go.
[Thufir] Shield Wall.
Protects the city
from the weather
and the worms.
[eerie dramatic music playing]
[Gurney] The locals call
the big one the Hand of God.
[Leto] Well, the Hand of God
is wreaking havoc
on our comms system.
It's so quiet.
[Gurney] Yeah.
That's what worries me, too.
[Leto] There's the spaceport
and that plume of dust there
is the spice refinery.
Our two
most vulnerable points.
I want you guarding them.
If we can't refine spice
and ship it off-world,
-we're dead here.
-[Lanville] My lord.
The sun's getting too high.
We need to seal the doors.
[Leto sighs]
What do they say
about this hellhole again?
"To shower, you scrub your ass
with sand," my lord.
That's what they say.
[Thufir] Candidates
for a housekeeper, my lady.
What is your name?
Shadout Mapes, my lady.
[Lady Jessica]
The rest of you may go.
Thank you.
Shadout.
It's an old Chakobsa word.
"Well-dipper."
[speaking Chakobsa]
[in English]
You know the ancient tongues?
I know many things.
I know that you have a weapon
concealed in your bodice.
[in sign language]
[speaking]
If you mean to harm me,
I must warn you,
whatever you're hiding,
it won't be enough.
The weapon is meant as a gift
if you are truly The One.
Do you know this?
It's a crysknife.
Do you know its meaning?
[in sign language]
It's a maker...
[wailing]
A maker of the deep desert.
When you have lived
with prophecy for so long,
the moment of revelation
is a shock.
Lisan al-Gaib.
The mother and the son.
It is yours.
Tooth of  Shai-Hulud.
[ancient meditation music
playing]
[men chanting in distance]
Lisan! Lisan al-Gaib!
Lisan al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
[Paul] Hello.
You shouldn't be out here
at this hour of the day.
They're out here.
[gardener] Hmm.
Fremen pilgrims.
They don't care
about heatstroke.
I didn't know date palms
could even be found out here.
[gardener] Oh,
these aren't indigenous.
They can't survive without me.
Each one of these
drinks every day
the equivalent of five men.
Twenty palm trees.
A hundred lives.
Should we remove them?
Save the water?
No, no, no.
These are sacred.
Old dream.
[narrator over speakers]
The largest and most dangerous
organism on Arrakis
is the sandworm,
capable of reaching
400 meters in length.
To avoid making
rhythmic noises,
which attract the sandworms,
the Fremen cross desert spaces
using the sandwalk,
a dance-like motion
with irregular rhythm
which emulates the natural
sounds of the desert.
What scant plant life
exists on Arrakis
is thanks to the Fremen,
who have cultivated
deep-rooted terranic plants
such as saguaro, burrobush,
sand-verbena and incense bush.
The shepherd's tree has
the deepest documented roots,
stretching more than
450 feet deep.
These plants cling to life
in a parched,
nutrient-poor landscape.
[slow suspenseful music
playing]
[music building up]
[both gasp]
[Paul] It's a hunter-seeker.
The operator must be nearby.
[dramatic music playing]
[Thufir]  The Harkonnen agent
was cemented
into that hole six weeks ago.
Ran the hunter-seeker
through a water pipe
inside the walls.
Sire, I failed you today.
There's no excuse.
You have my resignation.
You would deprive us
of your talents at this time?
Sire, my honor demands...
They tried to take
the life of my son!
I don't give a damn
about your honor.
You want absolution?
Go catch some spies.
Your Grace.
[Mohiam] The thing must leave.
[man] You can speak
without fear.
Our pet doesn't understand
your language.
[Mohiam in distorted voice]
Get out.
[normal voice] It understands.
Activate silence.
[low, muffled speech]
[Mohiam] It must
never be known.
[Vladimir] There's
no satellites over Arrakis.
The Atreides
will die in the dark.
[Mohiam] On that matter,
Duke Leto Atreides
means nothing to our order.
But his wife
is under our protection
and by extension, her son.
Allow them
the dignity of exile.
[sighs]
House Harkonnen
would never dream
of violating
the sanctity of your order.
I give you my word.
We will not harm them.
If the Duke's son lives...
No Atreides will live.
My lord, you gave your word
to the witch.
She sees too much.
I said I would not harm them.
And I shall not.
But Arrakis is Arrakis.
And the desert takes the weak.
My desert.
[sinister music playing]
My Arrakis.
My Dune.
[Gurney] Your first
strategy meeting.
Paul Atreides,
who catches hunter-seekers
in his bare hands
like a hero of old.
[laughter]
[whispers] Thanks
for the humiliation, old man.
Gotta keep an eye on you.
Attention!
Let's get started.
Thufir. Operations.
I secured a copy of
the Harkonnens' account books.
[men murmuring]
The Harkonnens were taking
10 billion solaris
out of here every year.
"They shall suck of
the abundance of the seas,
and the treasure
hid in the sand."
[Thufir] We won't see profits
like that for a while.
Not with the equipment
they left us.
How bad is it?
[Thufir] These are spice silos.
We're meant
to fill every crate.
[Paul] All of them?
Every 25 standard days.
Harkonnen sabotage
slows us down.
[Paul] But who's
meant to arbitrate?
Isn't there
a Judge of the Change
to oversee the transition?
Who did the Emperor appoint?
Dr. Liet Kynes.
Imperial Ecologist.
Been here 20 years.
Eccentric, from what I'm told.
I want to see these
harvesting fields myself.
I wouldn't recommend it,
my lord.
Have this Judge of the Change
accompany us.
A meeting's long overdue.
And we'll get
a bit of Imperial protection.
A hostage. [chuckles]
I love it.
Hmm.
-[engine roaring]
-He's here, my lord.
[Duncan well-wishing
in Chakobsa]
[in English] Take care
of them. They are friends.
[Paul] Duncan!
[Duncan] Ah! My boy!
[both laughing]
I swear you're getting taller.
[Paul] Well,
you smell much worse.
For four weeks,
I lived with the Fremen.
Hidden in the desert,
in a community
called a  sietch.
Stilgar, the leader
of that  sietch,
has come with me
to meet you, sire.
This  sietch,  how is it hidden?
It's underground.
Arrakis is filled
with caverns.
How big was the place?
I'd say 10,000 people.
And there are
hundreds of  sietches.
Millions of Fremen.
You were right.
The Harkonnen estimate was
50,000 on the whole planet.
The Fremen watched me
search for them for days.
I never saw them.
Finally, they sent
a warrior out to kill me.
And I gotta tell you,
I have never come
so close to dying.
There's no finer fighter
in the Imperium.
They fight like demons.
Desert power.
Duncan.
-Well done.
-Thank you, my lord.
[man] Sire.
Their leader has a knife
he won't surrender, sire.
It's a crysknife.
It's sacred to his people.
Let him pass.
[Gurney] Stop there.
Hey! Hey!
Mm.
[Leto] Stilgar.
Welcome.
Sir, I respect
the personal dignity
of any man that respects mine.
[inhales deeply]
[Stilgar] Hmm.
[Duncan] Hold.
[clears throat]
Thank you, Stilgar,
for the gift
of your body's moisture.
We accept it in the spirit
in which it was given.
[Leto snorts]
[Leto] I'm glad you've come.
I believe your people and mine
have much
to offer one another.
No, no, you are Outworlders.
You come here for the spice,
you take it,
giving nothing in return.
That's true.
I know you've suffered
at the hands of the Harkonnen.
Name what you want.
If it's in my power to grant,
I'll give it
and ask for nothing.
Mm. I ask for this.
Do not seek our  sietches.
Do not trespass in our lands.
The desert was ours
long before you came.
So, come and dig your spice,
but when you have it,
go back to this side
of the Shield Wall
and leave the desert
to the Fremen.
You will address the Duke
as "my lord" or "sire."
[Leto] Gurney, just...
Just a moment.
The Emperor
has given me Arrakis
as my fief
to rule and protect.
I cannot promise
not to travel into the desert
if duty compels me.
But your  sietches
will be yours forever.
And you will never be hunted
while I govern here.
That's very honorable.
I must go. That's all
I have to say to you.
[Paul] Won't you stay?
We would honor you.
Honor requires
that I be elsewhere.
[speaking Chakobsa]
I don't like him.
Our plan bears fruit.
But it will take time?
Yes.
It will take time.
Here, this is for you.
It's a paracompass.
The moons here
have a magnetic field, so...
a simple compass needle
won't point north.
Takes a clever piece
of clockwork to sort it out.
[Paul] The Fremen make these?
And stillsuits,
and sand compactors,
and all kinds
of ingenious things.
[Gurney] What the hell
is a sand compactor?
[Duncan]
That's a sand compactor.
[all chuckle]
My God, man,
you've gone native.
You admire them.
I do.
They're fierce but loyal.
They're attuned to the desert.
Part of it.
It's part of them.
You wait till you see it.
It's beautiful out there.
[announcer]
Sunrise warning, all workers.
Temperature today
will reach 140 degrees.
We are currently 90 degrees,
and in 10 minutes,
we will hit 120 degrees.
Last warning call.
[dramatic music playing]
[dramatic music continues]
The Judge of the Change, sire.
Dr. Liet Kynes.
My lord Duke.
Welcome to Arrakis.
[Paul] You're
the Imperial Ecologist.
Thank you for the stillsuits.
They are of Fremen make.
The best.
With your permission, sire,
I must check
the integrity of your suit...
[Leto] Whoa.
It's all right.
[chuckles lightly] Dr. Kynes,
we're in your hands.
A stillsuit
is a high-efficiency
filtration system.
Even this early
in the morning,
you wouldn't survive two hours
without one of these.
It cools the body
and recycles
the water lost to sweat.
Your body's movements
provide the power.
Inside the mask,
you'll find a tube
to allow you to drink
the recycled water.
[Leto] Mm.
In good working order,
your suit won't lose
more than a thimbleful
of water a day.
[Leto] Most impressive.
Let's have a look at you, lad.
You've...
worn a stillsuit before?
No, this is my first time.
Your desert boots are fitted
slip-fashion at the ankles.
Who taught you to do that?
It seemed the right way.
[speaking Chakobsa]
[in English] Are you Fremen?
I am accepted
in both  sietch  and village.
Now, come and see
the spice sands
on which
your livelihood depends.
[dramatic music playing]
What would you do
if your ornithopter
went down out here?
You wouldn't want
to go down out there.
It's worm territory.
Dust cloud.
[Leto] I see it.
That's one of your harvesters.
[dramatic music continues]
[machinery clunking]
[Dr. Kynes]
You can see the spice
scattered over the surface.
A rich spice bed
by the color.
If you get a little higher,
you'll have a better view.
You see these spotter aircraft
looking for wormsign.
[Paul] Wormsign?
A sand wave
moving toward the crawler.
Worms travel deep
but get closer
to the surface
when they attack.
If you are patient,
we should see one.
A worm always comes?
Always. They're drawn
by rhythmic noises.
Why don't we just shield
the crawlers?
A shield's a death sentence
in the desert.
It attracts the worms
and drives them
into a killing frenzy.
Is that a worm?
[Dr. Kynes] Big one.
You have good eyes.
Calling crawler
Delta Ajax niner.
Wormsign warning. Acknowledge.
[Crawler over radio]
Who calls Delta Ajax niner?
Over.
They seem pretty calm
about it.
[Dr. Kynes] Unlisted flight.
Imperium business.
Wormsign north
and east of you.
3.7 kilometers.
[Spotter over radio]
Delta Ajax niner,
this is Spotter One.
Wormsign confirmed.
Stand by for contact fix.
Worm is on intercept course
to your position.
Contact in five minutes.
So, what happens now?
They'll call a carryall
to lift the crawler.
They'll harvest right up
to the last minute.
[Crawler]  Calling
carryall Alpha Zero.
Ready for docking sequence.
Contact five minutes. Over.
[Spotter]  Anybody got a visual
on the carryall?
[Dr. Kynes] There it is.
[Carryall over radio]
This is carryall Alpha Zero
to Delta Ajax niner.
Approaching from your east.
Correcting altitude and
preparing docking equipment.
[Crawler]  Copy, Alpha Zero.
Initiating docking sequence.
[Carryall]  T-5.
[man]  Copy that.
[Crawler]  Prepare
to be airborne in 30 seconds.
[Carryall]  Docking sequence
initiated. Brace yourselves.
[explosion]
[man]  Alpha Zero, we're short
one point of contact.
[Crawler]  What is going on?
[Carryall]  It's one of
the anchors. It's dead.
[Dr. Kynes] Shit.
[Carryall]  Carryall
unable to receive.
Unable to lift
without that anchor.
[Crawler]  All call! All call!
Any carryall in the sector,
please respond!
Spotter One,
give us an update. Over.
[Carryall]  Hydraulics are dead.
We won't make it.
You have to evacuate.
[announcer over radio]
Contact in four minutes.
[Crawler]  Try it again!
How many men on that crawler?
Crew of 21.
[Leto] Our ships
can take six each.
That's still three short.
We'll find a way.
[over radio]
This is Duke Leto Atreides.
We're coming down to extract
the crew of Delta Ajax niner.
We'll set down on the west.
Shield generators
weigh 100 kilos each.
Yes, Gurney,
have our escorts throw out
the shield generators.
[Gurney] Yes, sire.
[Leto] And, Paul, I want you
at the back of the thopter.
Guide them in.
Delta Ajax niner,
put seven men each
in my ships now.
[suspenseful music playing]
[ethereal music playing]
[machinery clanking]
[announcer over radio]
Contact in two minutes.
[indistinct radio chatter]
[Spotter]  Getting close, guys.
We better abandon ship now.
[indistinct radio chatter]
Where are they?
[Crawler]  Sir,
there's protocol for a reason.
If we take one step out there,
we're as good as dead.
Besides, we've got
a full load of spice.
-We can't just leave it.
-Damn the spice!
I want every man
off that crawler now!
[tense music playing]
Hey!
Seven over here,
seven over there.
Go! Go! Go!
[tense music stops]
[ethereal music playing]
[eerie voices murmur]
[eerie voices]
Kwisatz Haderach.
[eerie voices murmuring
indistinctly]
Kwisatz Haderach  awakes.
[tense music playing]
[Gurney] Hurry! Get on!
[men shout hurriedly]
[Dr. Kynes] It's here!
[Leto] Paul!
Paul!
[quietly] I recognize
your footsteps, old man.
Get up!
Let's go!
What's the matter with you?
Come on! Let's go!
Run!
[tense music continues]
[grunting]
[Gurney] Hey!
Bless the Maker and His Water.
Bless the coming
and going of Him.
May His passage
cleanse the world
and keep the world
for His people.
[sandworm roars]
Hey!
-You cannot take such risks.
-[Paul] Yes, sir.
You have responsibilities.
I... I'm sorry, sir.
It won't happen again.
Go.
Dr. Kynes.
You saw it.
With your own eyes.
It's plain to see.
Everything they've left us
is in shambles.
We've been set up to fail.
That carryall was just old.
The desert
isn't kind to equipment.
You know what will happen
if I don't get spice
production back on track.
[scoffs]
I'm not here
to take your part.
Arrakis has seen men like you
come and go.
Take good care of your family.
The desert's not kind
to humans either.
Spice is a psychoactive
chemical.
You seem to be sensitive.
You'll be fine.
Thank you, Dr. Yueh.
That wasn't
an allergic reaction.
I had a vision.
My eyes were wide open.
What did you see?
[eerie ethereal music playing]
[eerie voices]
Kwisatz Haderach.
You can see.
[Paul]  It's confusing.
I thought I saw my death,
only it wasn't.
I know a knife is important,
somehow.
Someone will hand me a blade,
but I don't know who,
or when, or where.
Some things, though,
are crystal clear.
I can feel it.
I know you're pregnant.
You can't know that.
I barely know that.
It's only been a few weeks.
[priest throat-singing
in Sardaukar]
[Bashar speaking Sardaukar]
[Piter in English]
Atreides legions
are the finest
in the Imperium.
Trained by Gurney Halleck
and Duncan Idaho.
[speaking Sardaukar]
[in English] Just so.
Three battalions.
As agreed.
[continues throat-singing]
[all grunt]
[speaking Sardaukar]
[whimpering]
[crying softly]
There is something
you need to know about Paul.
[Leto] No.
Don't think I want to know.
Ever since you brought him
before your Reverend Mother,
he hasn't been the same.
He's distracted.
Jessica, you gave me a son.
And from the moment
he was born,
I never questioned you.
I trusted you completely.
Even when
you walked in shadows.
Now I'm asking you
this one thing.
If anything happens...
will you protect our son?
With my life.
I'm not asking his mother.
I'm asking the Bene Gesserit.
Will you protect Paul?
Why are you
having these thoughts?
Leto, this is not you.
I thought we'd have more time.
[Dr. Yueh] Have a good night,
Master Paul.
[Paul] Good night, Dr. Yueh.
[Lady Jessica]
You need to sleep.
No.
Not like that.
[Leto sighs deeply]
I should have married you.
[footsteps]
[weapon firing]
[guards groaning]
[wheezing]
[shield powering down]
[low tense music playing]
[soft grunt]
[softly] Hawat. Security.
[normal tone] Security.
[device beeps]
[choking]
[stifled grunt]
[dart fires]
[shield crackling]
[groaning]
[tense music playing]
[whimpers]
[Lieutenant] Sir. Sir.
The shield's come down.
-[alarm blaring]
-[soldiers clamoring]
[Gurney] God in heaven.
Get everything with guns
off the ground! Go!
[soldiers shouting]
[dramatic music playing]
[missile whistles]
Go! Go! Go!
[soldiers screaming]
[missile whistles]
[grunting]
[groans]
With me! With me!
[soldiers yelling]
[dramatic music continues]
[marching footsteps]
[Lieutenant] Atreides!
[guards] Atreides!
[all grunting in unison]
[synchronized grunting]
[all grunting]
-[Atreides guard 1] Sardaukar!
-[Atreides guard 2] Sardaukar!
[groaning]
I'm sorry, my lord.
But I've made a bargain
with the Baron.
[Leto breathing raggedly]
Why?
I had no choice.
The Harkonnens
have my wife, Wanna.
They take her apart
like a doll.
I will buy her freedom.
And you are the price.
For Paul.
I will do what I can.
And you
will kill a man for me.
I'm going to replace
your peg tooth.
If you bite down hard,
this tooth will crush.
Breathe out, and you will
fill the air with poison.
It will be your last breath.
But if you choose
your moment well,
it will also be the Baron's.
[tense music playing]
[yelling]
[soldiers speak indistinctly]
[soldier groans]
[grunts]
Paul.
[door closes]
[trooper 1 speaking Harkonnen]
[trooper 2 speaking]
[trooper 1 speaking]
[in sign language]
[all grunting]
[Duncan] To hell, dogs!
[grunts]
[alarm beeping]
[trooper 1 in English]
I've never had a highborn.
You?
Bene Gesserit
ain't all highborn.
[trooper 1]
She's highborn enough for me.
Let's feed the kid
to the worms.
And give her a long goodbye.
Don't you dare
touch my mother.
Don't talk.
[in sign language]
[Paul sighs]
[sternly] Remove her gag.
[retches]
[trooper 1] Shut up.
[in sign language]
[panting]
[trooper 1 speaking Harkonnen]
[Paul breathing deeply]
[in distorted voice]
Remove her gag.
[in distorted voice] Kill him.
[in distorted voice]
Set us free.
[speaking Harkonnen]
[trooper 1 groans]
[Lady Jessica grunting]
[in distorted voice] Stop!
Cut the rope.
Give me the knife.
[stabs]
[grunts]
[in normal voice]
Your pitch was too forced.
[Paul] It's a fremkit.
[man speaks Harkonnen
over radio]
[engine shuts off]
They've crippled the ship.
[distant explosions]
[gasping]
[sighs]
[explosions continue]
[wheezing softly]
[man] Mmm.
[Vladimir grunts softly]
[cutlery clinking]
[Vladimir grunts]
Ah.
[munching]
You have a wonderful kitchen,
cousin.
[wind howling]
[Paul grunts]
This is Dr. Yueh's
handwriting.
"If anyone makes it out
of Arrakeen alive,
there's an Atreides beacon
in the fremkit.
God willing,
they'll be able to find you."
[wheezing weakly]
My lord Baron.
Dr. Yueh.
[Vladimir] The traitor.
What do you want?
I jammed their comms
and lowered their shields.
[Vladimir] Hmm.
[Dr. Yueh] I delivered
the Duke and his family.
[Vladimir] The bargain
to the letter.
And what was I to do for you?
Deliver my wife
from her agony.
[Vladimir] Yes.
[slow sinister music playing]
[chewing loudly]
I said I'd set her free.
That you could join her.
[Dr. Yueh grunts]
So, join her.
-[knife slices]
-[body thuds]
What do you think is next?
[Paul] It's a thumper.
No stillsuits.
The one thing
we actually need.
For hundreds of years,
we've traded blood for blood.
But no more.
Your son is dead.
Your concubine is dead.
Tonight
the House of Atreides falls.
And your bloodline
ends forever.
[Leto mumbling]
What did you say?
[softly] Here I am...
here I remain.
[tooth crunches]
[exhales forcefully]
-[gasping]
-[dramatic music playing]
[Piter coughs]
[cries softly]
[soft music playing]
[dramatic lamentation music
playing]
[engine roaring in distance]
[Duncan] Kynes!
It's not safe for you here.
[Duncan] Will you tell
the Great Houses
of the Landsraad
how we were betrayed?
How the best of them
were murdered?
I am commanded to say nothing.
To see nothing.
The Emperor
sent us here to die.
[lamentation music continues]
[man choking]
[strained breathing]
[coughing]
[Paul] There's spice
in the tent.
[coughing]
[clears throat]
[slow dramatic music playing]
[voices whispering
indistinctly]
[soldiers clamoring]
[panting]
[slow ominous music playing]
That's the future.
It's coming.
[ominous music continues]
Holy war
spreading across the universe
like unquenchable fire.
[voices continue whispering]
[thunder rumbling]
Paul, you're scared.
I can see it.
Tell me, please,
what do you fear?
[voices continue whispering]
Somebody help me, please.
Paul.
It's coming.
I see a holy war spreading
across the universe
like unquenchable fire.
A warrior religion
that waves the Atreides banner
in my father's name.
[Lady Jessica] Paul.
Fanatical legions worshipping
at the shrine
of my father's skull.
A war in my name!
Everyone's shouting my name!
Paul.
Paul Atreides.
You are your father's son.
You are my son.
You are
the Duke Paul Atreides.
You know who you are.
[in distorted voice]
Get off me!
[normal voice]
You did this to me!
You Bene Gesserit
made me a freak!
[breathing heavily]
[Paul crying]
My father is dead.
[Paul sobbing]
[mournful music playing]
[device beeping]
[Paul softly] Someone's near.
You need to drink.
It's recycled water
from the tent.
Sweat and tears.
All right,
let's get out of here.
[device whirring]
[shield buzzing]
[squeaks]
[whimpers]
[muffled whirring]
[grunting and panting]
[squeaks]
[Paul grunts]
[Lady Jessica panting]
[engine roaring]
That's Duncan.
Duncan.
[panting]
My lady.
Paul.
I'm so sorry. Your father...
We know.
My lord Duke.
Here.
Drink this.
[Duncan] Harkonnens hit
every population center
on the planet at once.
There must have been
10 legions, hundreds of ships.
There were Sardaukar
with them.
-At least two battalions.
-What? Are you sure?
You cross swords
with a Sardaukar,
you know it.
[Lady Jessica sighs] So,
the Emperor's taken a side.
What says
the Judge of the Change?
The Emperor forbids me
from saying anything at all.
And yet you risk your life
to help us.
[thunder rumbling]
[man shouting]
-[thunder continues rumbling]
-[clamoring]
[worker] Storm's coming.
[workers shouting
indistinctly]
[Dr. Kynes] The storm
will be here in a few hours.
We'll be safe here.
Do you know
what this place is?
It's an old
ecological testing station.
They were meant
to tame the planet.
Free the water
locked beneath the sands.
Arrakis could have been
a paradise.
The work had begun,
but then the spice
was discovered.
And suddenly no one
wanted the desert to go away.
Tanat,
will you find stillsuits
to fit our visitors?
TANAT: Yes, Liet.
[Dr. Kynes] Shamir,
a coffee service, please.
SHAMIR: Of course, Liet.
[door unlocks]
Who are you to the Fremen?
[indistinct chatter]
[wind howling]
[Paul] You know what
the Great Houses fear most,
Dr. Kynes?
Exactly what has happened
to us here.
The Sardaukar coming
and picking them off
one by one.
Only together
can they stand a chance
against the Imperium.
Would you bear witness?
Testify that the Emperor
has moved against us here?
If they believe me,
there would be general warfare
between the Great Houses
and the Emperor.
Chaos
across the Imperium.
Suppose I presented
the Emperor
with an alternative to chaos.
The Emperor has no sons.
And his daughters
have yet to marry.
You'd make a play
for the throne?
The Emperor
feared the Atreides.
He brought you here
to kill you.
What don't you understand?
You're a lost boy hiding
in a hole in the ground.
The Fremen speak
of the  Lisan al-Gaib.
Careful.
The Voice from the Outer World
who will lead them
to paradise.
Superstition.
I know you loved
a Fremen warrior
and lost him in battle.
I know you walk in two worlds
and are known by many names.
I've seen your dream.
As emperor, Dr. Kynes,
I could make
a paradise of Arrakis
with a wave of my hand.
[man speaking Chakobsa]
[man 2 shushing]
[soldier speaking Sardaukar]
-[explosions]
-[all grunting]
-[blades slicing]
-[groaning]
[muffled thudding]
[suspenseful music playing]
Sardaukar!
No! Duncan!
[Lady Jessica] Paul, no!
-[Paul] Duncan, no!
-[Lady Jessica] No!
-[Paul] No!
-[Lady Jessica] Paul, no!
[Paul] Duncan, no!
-He's locked the door.
-[Paul] Duncan! No!
[slow choral music playing]
[all grunting]
[tense music playing]
[Duncan groans]
[soldier speaks Sardaukar]
[shield crackling]
He's gone.
[Paul] Duncan!
We have to go.
We have no choice.
[tense music continues]
[laser firing]
[Lady Jessica] Paul, go! Paul!
[Duncan yelling]
[Dr. Kynes] Come on.
Come on, come on!
[shield buzzing]
[speaks Sardaukar]
[tense music continues]
[panting] Follow the light.
You'll find a thopter
ready to fly.
That storm out there
is your best shot.
Above 5,000 meters,
it's mostly dust.
Climb into it. Stay on top.
Head south. Find the Fremen.
Are you not coming with us?
It only seats two.
I'll go to the next station
and report this attack
to the Landsraad.
[Lady Jessica] How?
I'm Fremen.
The desert's my home.
Good luck.
[Paul] Good luck.
[dramatic tense music playing]
[switches clicking]
[engine sputtering]
[engine rumbles]
[engine starts]
[blade stabs]
-[blade retracts]
-[groans]
[dramatic lamentation music
playing]
[assassin speaking Sardaukar]
[in English]
I serve only one master.
His name is  Shai-Hulud.
[pounding rhythmically]
[speaks Sardaukar]
[assassin grunts]
[assassins grunting]
[grunts]
[panicked chatter]
-[sandworm roars]
-[assassins screaming]
[switches click]
[ominous music playing]
There are jet flares
behind us.
[Lady Jessica grunting]
[alarm wailing]
[engine accelerating]
Paul. We're not high enough!
[missile whistling]
-[metal rattling]
-[explosion]
-[metallic clanking]
-[Paul gasps]
-[clanking continues]
-[metal squeaks]
[engine rumbling]
[metal rattling]
I must not fear.
Fear is the mind-killer.
Fear is the little death
that brings obliteration.
[rumbling and clanking stop]
[voices whispering]
See the friend.
[Jamis]  The mystery of life
isn't a problem to solve...
but a reality to experience.
A process
that cannot be understood
by stopping it.
We must move
with the flow of the process.
We must join it.
We must flow with it.
[voices]  Let go.
Let go.
[switches click]
[engine humming]
[bubbling]
[servant speaking Harkonnen]
-[water bubbling]
-[breathes heavily]
[in English] We chased them
into a Coriolis storm.
Winds at 800 kilometers
an hour.
Nothing survives such a storm.
They're dead.
It's a certainty.
[grunts]
So, it's done. Finally.
Send word to Giedi Prime
to begin selling
our spice reserves.
But slowly.
We don't want
the price to fall.
You have no idea
how much it cost me
to bring such a force
to bear here.
Now I only have
one requirement.
Income.
So, squeeze, Rabban.
Squeeze hard.
Yes, Uncle.
And the Fremen?
Kill them all.
[wind gusting]
[alarm beeping rapidly]
[Paul] We're above
5,000 meters.
[engine roars]
[exhales sharply]
[ornithopter rattling]
[Paul grunting]
[engine roaring]
[alarm beeping rapidly]
[sputtering]
-[metallic rattling]
-[gasping]
[gasps]
[alarm continues beeping]
[switches click]
[alarm stops beeping]
[soft rattling]
[wind whistling]
[rattling]
[both gasping]
[engine whines]
[Paul] As soon as we land,
run for the rocks.
[engine accelerates]
[Lady Jessica whimpering]
[engine roaring]
[both panting]
And breathe through this.
[rumbling]
[Paul over mask]  Now
we have to find the Fremen.
Are you good?
[Lady Jessica]  Yeah.
[slow suspenseful music
playing]
[voices echoing]  Paul...
Don't be frightened.
[girl]  Even a little
desert mouse can survive.
[voices]  Don't be frightened.
[girl]  You'll need
to face your fears.
[voices]  A friend...
A friend will help you.
Follow the friend.
[Jamis]
You have much to learn.
And I will show you
the ways of the desert.
Come with me.
[mysterious music playing]
[Paul]  The  sietch
where Duncan lived
is somewhere off that way.
[Lady Jessica]  I can see
greenery over there.
There.
[Paul]  That means
Fremen live there.
We'll cross after dark.
That's how the Fremen do it.
[Paul]  We're about to enter
worm territory.
We can't walk
like regular humans.
If we do, we're dead.
We'll have to walk
like the Fremen do.
It's called a sandwalk.
At least according
to the filmbooks back home.
[Lady Jessica]
Yeah. Yeah, okay.
[Paul]  Okay. Follow me.
Do the same moves.
[compass ticking]
I think this is
the right direction.
[both grunting]
[panting]
[distant rumbling]
[rumbling fades]
[Paul]  It's close by.
Let's get out of here.
-[thuds]
-Wait.
-[hollow thudding]
-It's drum sand.
[wind gusting]
-[gasps]
-[Paul]  run.
[tense music playing]
[Lady Jessica]  Go! Go!
[grunts]
[whimpering]
[rumbling stops]
[panting]
[sandworm moans]
[gasping]
[rhythmic thumping]
[thumping stops]
[soft rhythmic thumping]
[Paul]  It's a thumper.
Someone set off a thumper.
[thumping fades]
[rhythmic thumping]
[thumping stops]
[Lady Jessica]  Paul! Run!
[both panting]
How big are they?
That was insane.
[groans]
Someone called it.
[Lady Jasmine pants]
[in sign language]
[pebble clatters]
[footsteps]
[Stilgar over mask]
Do not run.
You will only waste
your body's water.
Hold.
Stilgar.
-[blade rustles]
-Hey!
You know me. I was there
when you came
to my father's Council.
[Stilgar] Oh.
This is the Duke's son.
[Jamis] Why are you waiting?
We need their water.
[Stilgar] This is the boy
I told you about.
We can't touch him.
[woman speaking Fremen]
[Jamis in English]
They are weaklings.
[Stilgar] Jamis.
That was a brave crossing
they made
in the path of  Shai-Hulud.
He does not speak
or act like a weakling.
Nor did his father.
[Jamis] My thumper
saved his life.
Go back to reason, Stilgar.
He's not The One.
[sighs]
We have powerful friends.
You help us off-world,
to Caladan,
you will be well rewarded.
What wealth can you offer
beyond the water
in your flesh?
[Stilgar] Hmm...
The boy is young.
He can learn our ways.
He may have sanctuary.
But the woman is untrained...
and too old to learn.
[low tense music playing]
[sniffles]
[grunting]
[groans]
-[both grunt]
-[Stilgar] back, you dogs.
She'll cut my throat.
Why didn't you say
you were a weirding woman?
And a fighter?
Conversation ran short.
[Stilgar] Peace, woman.
Peace.
I judged hastily.
[sniffs]
[Stilgar grunts]
[speaking Chakobsa]
[girl in English]  I would not
have let you hurt my friends.
They say you're the  Mahdi.
But you look
like a little boy.
You chose the hardest way up.
Follow me.
[Stilgar speaking Chakobsa]
[in English] Give it to me.
You will have
your own maula pistol
when you've earned it.
Give it to me.
Chani, take charge
of the newcomers.
See that they are safe
on the journey. Let's go.
[Jamis] I will not have them.
[Stilgar] Jamis,
I have spoken. Be still.
[Jamis] You talk like a leader.
But the strongest leads.
She bested you.
I invoke the amtal.
[Stilgar] You may not challenge
a  Sayyadina.
Then who will fight
in her name?
Jamis, don't do this.
Don't. The night is fading.
Then the sun
will witness this death.
Where is her champion?
I accept her champion.
[slow dramatic music playing]
[grunting]
[voices]  Paul Atreides
must die...
for  Kwisatz Haderach  to rise.
Don't be frightened.
Don't resist.
When you take a life,
you take your own.
[moans]
[breathing heavily]
I don't believe
you're the  Lisan al-Gaib.
But I want you
to die with honor.
This crysknife was given to me
by my great aunt.
It's made
from a tooth of  Shai-Hulud.
The great sandworm.
This will be a great honor,
for you to die holding it.
[Jamis shouts]
Where is the Outworlder?
Jamis is a good fighter.
He won't let you suffer.
Chani...
Um...
[scoffs]
Never mind.
[slow dramatic music
continues]
May thy knife
chip and shatter.
You should welcome my blade.
This world will kill you.
Quicker this way.
[spectators speak Chakobsa
in unison]
-[man speaks Chakobsa]
-[Jamis grunting]
[breathing heavily]
-Do you yield?
-[spectators exclaim]
[Stilgar speaking Chakobsa]
[Stilgar in English]
The boy doesn't know our rule.
[yells]
There's no yielding
under the amtal rule.
Only death is the test of it.
[Jamis yelling]
[both grunting]
-Is he toying with him?
-No.
Paul has never killed a man.
[both grunt]
[yelling]
[dramatic lamentation music
playing]
[voices] Kwisatz Haderach.
[yelling]
Kwisatz Haderach.
Climb up. Rise.
[stabs]
[grunts]
[Jamis groaning]
[mournful music playing]
[mournful music continues]
[speaking Chakobsa]
[in English]
You're one of us now.
A life for a life.
Come with us to  Sietch  Tabr.
No.
Paul needs to get off-world.
You must have ways.
You have smugglers,
you have ships.
-[Paul] No.
-[Lady Jessica] You have...
The Emperor sent us
to this place.
And my father came,
not for spice,
not for the riches,
but for the strength
of your people.
My road leads into the desert.
I can see it.
If you'll have us,
we will come.
[slow dramatic music playing]
Desert power.
This is only the beginning.